<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Ayurveda Health Care App</string>
    <string name="title_activity_doctor_location">Map</string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="title_activity_doctor_dashboard">MainActivity</string>
    <string name="title_home">Home</string>
    <string name="title_dashboard">Dashboard</string>
    <string name="title_notifications">Notifications</string>

    <string name="origin">Select Item</string>
    <string name="select">Select Item</string>
    <string-array name="type">
        <item>Tablet</item>
        <item>Liquid</item>
        <item>Cream</item>
        <item>Other</item>
    </string-array>


    <string name="new_1">Chronic Fever:
        When a person suffers from fever until 21 days and temperature does not become normal, it is called chronic fever. Sometimes, the temperature in this fever become high and sometimes low. If a person suffers from indigestion and weakness, he becomes the victim of chronic fever.
Treatment :

Prepare a decoction by boiling the bark of oval leaved rose way and tinospora and give to the patient to take. Or soak the bark of oval leaved rose way in the water at night and give this preparation after filtering to the patient. Both are beneficial in chronic fever.
Boil cow’s milk by mixing ghee, dry ginger and black grapes. Take it. Its use gets rid of chronic fever.\n
\t Grind equal quantity of chireta, dry ginger, Indian gooseberry (amla), sweet flag and tinospora. Fill it in a bottle. Then give 1-1 spoon of this preparation 3-4 times a day.
In the fever from which a patient has been suffering for 6 days and he gets no relief by any medicine, grind 40g tinospora properly and soak in 250 ml water filled in an earthen pot. Cover this pot and leave all over night. Crush this mixture in the morning and take 20 ml this preparation after filtering thrice a day. Its use provides relief in chronic fever.
Take 20 ml juice of tinospora after mixing 1g piper longum and one spoon honey in it in the morning and evening. Its use gets rid of chronic fever, cough, spleen diseases, phlegm, anorexia, etc.
To prevent headache due to fever, caused by dirty place, polluted environment and spoiled fruits-vegetables; boil 400 ml water with 10 to 20g leaves of white kachanar until it remains one-fourth. Now this decoction should be given to the patient.
It is very useful to take the decoction of neem’s bark after mixing coriander and dry ginger in it.\n
\tGrind 400 g leaves of neem, 120g dry ginger, black pepper, long peeper, triphala (Harad, Baheda and Aamla), all three types of salt, 80g impure carbonate of soda and impure carbonate of potash and 200g bishop’s weed to make powder. Now take this powder in the morning and evening. Its use provides relief in chronic fever.
Poisonous and chronic fever abates by taking the smoke of neem’s leaves, sweet flag, ghee, myrolealans, Indian bdellium and albizzia lebbeck (Shiras).
Prepare decoction by boiling equal quantity of neem’s bark, dry grapes and tinospora in 100 ml water. Take 20 ml this decoction in the morning, noon and evening for a few days regularly.
Tie 21 leaves of neem and 21 pieces of black pepper in muslin cloth to make a small bundle then boil it in 500 ml water until it remains one-fourth. Now give this water after cooling in the morning and evening to the patient in the condition of chronic fever. Its use provides relief to the patient of chronic fever.
Mix the juice of seedless unripe fresh fruits of bead tree with the same quantity of the juice of tinospora and one-fourth powder of bishop’s weed. Now make small tablets after grinding all properly. Then take 1-1 tablet thrice a day with fresh water. It gets rid of chronic fever.
Boil salt in water and take. Its use gets rid of malarial fever.\n
\tGrind 1 spoon powder of the bark of terminalia Arjuna with jiggery (gur). Its use gets rid of chronic fever.
If someone has been suffering from chronic fever along with cough and pain in the chest, it is useful to take the juice of basil’s leaves after mixing sugar candy in it.
 </string>
    <string name="new_2">
        <string name=""><b><big></big></b>
        \n <li>        *A deciduous tree with a flaky, brownish bark. Old trees yield a sticky sap when the stem is damaged.
</li>
        \n <li>*The young reddish-brown leaves turn bright green upon maturing, giving the canopy a bright green hue.
</li>
        \n <li>*Leaves are somewhat droopy, compound, 15-35 cm long, containing 10-12 pairs of leaflets arranged in opposites including the terminal pair.
</li>
            \n <li> *Leaflets are asymmetric with a prominent mid vein, strong-scented when crushed, about 5-9 cm long and 1.5-3.5 cm broad,
</li>
            \n <li>*with a pointed apex and teethed margin. Flowers are small, white, sweetly-scented, borne in terminal clusters during the months of March-May.
</li>
            \n <li>*Ellipsoid, fleshy fruits change colour from green to yellow when they ripen, about 1.5 cm in size, contains one seed.
</li>
            \n <li> *Fruit strewn on the ground is a common sight during the months of August- September.
</li>
    </string>
 </string>
    <string name="new_3">
        <string name=""><b><big></big></b>
        \n <li>       *Cumin is a spice native to the Mediterranean and Southwest Asia. It’s made from the seeds of the Cuminum cyminum plant, which are known for their distinctive earthy, nutty, and spicy flavor.
</li>
        \n <li>*Research shows that cumin may boost the activity of digestive enzymes and facilitate the release of bile from the liver, speeding digestion and easing the digestion of fats.
</li>
        \n <li>*Studies have also linked this Ayurvedic spice to reduced symptoms of irritable bowel syndrome (IBS), such as abdominal pain and bloating .
</li>
            \n <li>*Plus, cumin may protect against type 2 diabetes by lowering blood sugar levels and improving insulin sensitivity. It may also protect against heart disease by increasing HDL (good) cholesterol while reducing triglycerides and LDL (bad) cholesterol.
</li>
            \n <li>*Cumin likewise appears to possess antimicrobial properties that may reduce the risk of certain foodborne infections. Still, more studies are needed to confirm this
</li>
    </string>







 </string>
    <string name="new_4">
        <string name=""><b><big></big></b>
        \n <li>*Bitter melon (Momordica charantia) is a tropical vine closely related to zucchini, squash, cucumber, and pumpkin. It’s considered a staple in Asian cuisine and packed with nutrients and powerful antioxidants.
</li>
        \n <li>*Research suggests that bitter melon may help lower blood sugar levels and promote the secretion of insulin, the hormone responsible for keeping blood sugar levels stable .
</li>
        \n <li>*If you use insulin to manage your blood sugar levels, consult your healthcare before adding bitter melon to your daily routine to prevent your blood sugar levels from becoming dangerously low.
</li>
            \n <li>*Animal studies further suggest that it may lower triglyceride and LDL (bad) cholesterol levels, though human studies are needed to confirm this
</li>
    </string>



 </string>
    <string name="new_5">
        <string name=""><b><big></big></b>
        \n <li>        *Ashwagandha (Withania somnifera) is a small woody plant native to India and North Africa.</li>
        \n <li>        *Its root and berries are used to produce a very popular Ayurvedic remedy.
</li>
        \n <li>*It’s considered an adaptogen, which means that it’s believed to help your body manage stress more effectively.
</li>
            \n <li>        *Research has shown that it reduces levels of cortisol, a hormone that your adrenal glands produce in response to stress .
</li>
            \n <li>*There’s also evidence linking ashwagandha to lower levels of anxiety and improved sleep in people with stress and anxiety disorders .
</li>
            \n <li>*Moreover, research shows that ashwagandha may enhance muscle growth, memory, and male fertility, as well as lower blood sugar levels. However, larger studies are needed to confirm these benefits.
</li>
            \n <li>*Finally, there’s evidence that it may help reduce inflammation and boost your immune system, though more studies are needed
</li>
    </string>






 </string>
    <string name="new_6">
        <string name=" "><b><big></big></b>
        \n <li>        *Boswellia, also known as Indian frankincense or olibanum, is made from the resin of the Boswellia serrata tree.
</li>
        \n <li>       *It’s known for its easily recognizable spicy, woody aroma.
</li>
        \n <li>*Research suggests that it may be particularly effective at reducing inflammation by preventing the release of inflammation-causing compounds known as leukotrienes .
</li>
            \n <li>*In test-tube and animal studies, boswellia appears to be as effective as non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAIDs), yet with fewer side effects .
</li>
            \n <li>*Human studies link boswellia to reduced pain, improved mobility, and a greater range of movement in people with osteoarthritis and rheumatoid arthritis. It may also help prevent oral infections and fight gingivitis .
</li>
            \n <li>*Moreover, it may improve digestion in people with ulcerative colitis and Crohn’s disease, as well as breathing in people with chronic asthma
</li>
    </string>





 </string>
    <string name="new_7">
        <string name=""><b><big></big></b>
        \n <li>        *Turmeric, the spice that gives curry its characteristic yellow color, is another popular Ayurvedic remedy.
</li>
        \n <li>*Curcumin, its main active compound, has powerful antioxidant and anti-inflammatory properties.
</li>
        \n <li>        *Test-tube research shows that it may be equally or even more effective than some anti-inflammatory drugs — without all of their side effects .
</li>
            \n <li>*Also, turmeric may help protect against heart disease, in part by improving blood flow as effectively as exercise or certain pharmaceutical drugs.
</li>
            \n <li>       * One study further suggests that it may be as effective as Prozac, a drug commonly used to treat depression .
</li>
            \n <li>*Moreover, compounds in turmeric may help preserve brain function by increasing brain levels of brain-derived neurotrophic factor (BDNF).
</li>
            \n <li>        *Low levels of BDNF have been linked to disorders like Alzheimer’s and depression .
</li>
            \n <li>*That said, most studies have used very large amounts of curcumin, whereas turmeric comprises only around 3% of this compound.
</li>
            \n <li>        *Thus, amounts larger than those found in turmeric are likely needed to attain these health benefits, and such large doses may cause stomach upset
</li>
    </string>





    </string>
    <string name="new_8">
        <string name=""><b><big></big></b>
        \n <li>        *Licorice root, which is native to Europe and Asia, comes from the Glycyrrhiza glabra plant and holds a central place in Ayurvedic medicine.
</li>
        \n <li>*Test-tube and human studies suggest that licorice root may help reduce inflammation and fight viruses and bacteria.
</li>
        \n <li>        *It also appears to offer relief from a sore throat and promote oral health by protecting against dental cavities and Candida .
</li>
            \n <li>*This Ayurvedic spice may likewise help prevent or manage heartburn, bloating, nausea, belching, and stomach ulcers.
</li>
            \n <li>        *When applied to the skin, it may reduce symptoms of skin rash, including redness, itching, and swelling .
</li>
            \n <li>*However, the only studies on this root are generally small, and more research is needed to confirm these benefits.
</li>
    </string>





    </string>
    <string name="new_9">
        <string name=""><b><big></big></b>
        \n <li>        *Brahmi (Bacopa monieri) is a staple herb in Ayurvedic medicine.
</li>
        \n <li>*According to test-tube and animal studies, brahmi appears to have strong anti-inflammatory properties that are as effective as common NSAIDs.
</li>
        \n <li>*Studies also link it to improvements in learning rates, attention, memory, and information processing, as well as reduced symptoms of attention deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD), such as inattention, impulsivity, poor self-control, and restlessness.
</li>
            \n <li>*Some studies further suggest that brahmi may have adaptogenic properties, which means that it may help improve your body’s ability to deal with stress and anxiety. However, more research is needed before strong conclusions can be made
</li>
    </string>





    </string>


    <string name="med_1">
        <string name="Using for dry skin"><b><big>Using for dry skin</big></b>
        \n <li>*Preparations made from the plant Aloe vera are often referred to as "aloe vera"</li>
        \n <li>        *Scientific evidence for the cosmetic and therapeutic effectiveness of aloe vera is limited and when present is frequently contradictory.
</li>
        \n <li>        *Despite this, the cosmetic and alternative medicine industries regularly make claims regarding the soothing, moisturizing, and healing properties of aloe vera.
</li>
            \n <li>       *Aloe vera gel is used as an ingredient in commercially available lotions, yogurt, beverages, and some desserts, although at certain doses, it has toxic properties when used either for ingested or topical applications.
 </li>
    </string>



    </string>
    <string name="new_11"> <string name=""><b><big></big></b>
        \n <li>*The normal human body temperature is about 98.6°F, but it fluctuates throughout the day. A fever is when the temperature rises above a normal range.
</li>
        \n <li>*A low grade fever occurs when the body temperature becomes very slightly elevated, usually between about 100.5°F and 102.2°F. The fever is persistent when the body temperature stays in this range for more than 2 weeks.
</li>
        \n <li>*A fever is commonly a result of the body trying to fight off an infection or another illness. However, some cases are more difficult to diagnose and treat.
</li>
            \n <li>*Continue reading to learn more about the symptoms, causes, and treatment of a persistent low grade fever.
</li>

    </string>
    </string>
    <string name="new_12"><string name=""><b><big></big></b>
        \n <li>*Thigh pain can cause you to have difficulty walking, running, or climbing stairs. Sometimes the pain can occur after trauma or an injury. Other times, it may begin for no apparent reason.
</li>
        \n <li>*Your thigh is the area of your upper leg between your hip joint and your knee. It consists of several parts
</li>
        \n <li>*There are many different causes of thigh pain—some obvious and others not so much. Understanding your thigh pain and what may be causing it is the first step to properly treating your condition
</li>
            \n <li>*Both herniated lumbar discs and low back arthritis may pinch on the nerves that exit your spinal column and travel down your thigh, resulting in thigh pain
</li>

    </string>
    </string>
    <string name="new_13"><string name=""><b><big></big></b>
        \n <li>*Cross-training is important to becoming a stronger runner, but sometimes it can be hard to know where to start when switching up your routine.
</li>
        \n <li>*You’ll still get the cardio benefits and it will help strengthen your leg muscles, but spinning pedals with cycling helps you log workouts without pounding the pavement, which can take some pressure off your joints, making this ideal cross-training.
</li>
        \n <li>*To help you get started, professional triathlete Linsey Corbin shared her insights on the benefits of running and cycling, tips for success, and her favorite cycling workout.
</li>

    </string>
    </string>
    <string name="new_14"><string name=""><b><big></big></b>
        \n <li>*Healthy nails appear smooth and have consistent coloring. As you age, you may develop vertical ridges, or your nails may be a bit more brittle. This is harmless. Spots due to injury should grow out with the nail
</li>
        \n <li>*Abnormalities — such as spots, discoloration, and nail separation — can result from injuries to the fingers and hands, viral warts (periungual warts), infections (onychomycosis), and some medications, such as those used for chemotherapy.
</li>
        \n <li>*Some changes in your nails are due to medical conditions that need attention. See your doctor if you have any of these symptoms:

discoloration (dark streaks, white streaks, or changes in nail color)
changes in nail shape (curling or clubbing)
changes in nail thickness (thickening or thinning)
nails that become brittle
nails that are pitted
bleeding around nails
swelling or redness around nails
pain around nails
a nail separating from the skin
</li>

    </string></string>
    <string name="new_15"><string name=""><b><big></big></b>
        \n <li>*Your legs are made up of bones, blood vessels, muscles, and other connective tissue. They are important for motion and standing.
</li>
        \n <li>*Playing sports, running, falling, or having an accident can damage your legs. Common leg injuries include sprains and strains, joint dislocations, and fractures (broken bones).
</li>
        \n <li>*These injuries can affect the entire leg, or just the foot, ankle, knee, or hip. Certain diseases also lead to leg problems
</li>
            \n <li>*For example, knee osteoarthritis, common in older people, can cause pain and limited motion. Problems in your veins in your legs can lead to varicose veins or deep vein thrombosis.
</li>

    </string></string>
    <string name="new_16"><string name=""><b><big></big></b>
        \n <li>*Methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus (MRSA) is a cause of staph infection that is difficult to treat because of resistance to some antibiotics.
</li>
        \n <li>*Staph infections—including those caused by MRSA—can spread in hospitals, other healthcare facilities, and in the community where you live, work, and go to school.
</li>
        \n <li>*You can help prevent infections and stop the spread of MRSA.
</li>
            \n <li>*MRSA is responsible for several difficult-to-treat infections in humans.
</li>

    </string></string>
    <string name="new_17"><string name=""><b><big></big></b>
        \n <li>*Burns are tissue damage that results from heat, overexposure to the sun or other radiation, or chemical or electrical contact.
</li>
        \n <li>*Burns can be minor medical problems or life-threatening emergencies.
</li>
        \n <li>*The treatment of burns depends on the location and severity of the damage. Sunburns and small scalds can usually be treated at home.
</li>
            \n <li>*Deep or widespread burns need immediate medical attention. Some people need treatment at specialized burn centers and monthslong follow-up care.
</li>

    </string></string>


    <string name="new_18"><string name=""><b><big></big></b>
        \n <li>*Chest pain appears in many forms, ranging from a sharp stab to a dull ache. Sometimes chest pain feels crushing or burning.
</li>
        \n <li>*In certain cases, the pain travels up the neck, into the jaw, and then spreads to the back or down one or both arms.
</li>
        \n <li>*Many different problems can cause chest pain. The most life-threatening causes involve the heart or lungs.
</li>
            \n <li>*Because chest pain can indicate a serious problem, it is important to seek immediate medical help.
</li>

    </string></string>
    <string name="new_19"><string name=""><b><big></big></b>
        \n <li>*WebMD Symptom Checker helps you find the most common medical conditions indicated by the symptoms anxiety, depressed mood, fits of rage and forgetfulness including Depression (Adult), Alzheimer disease, and Generalized anxiety disorder.
</li>
        \n <li>*There are 32 conditions associated with anxiety, depressed mood, fits of rage and forgetfulness
</li>
        \n <li>*The links below will provide you with more detailed information on these medical conditions from the WebMD Symptom Checker and help provide a better understanding of causes and treatment of these related conditions.
</li>


    </string></string>
</resources>