<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Ayurveda Health Care App</string>
    <string name="title_activity_doctor_location">Map</string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="title_activity_doctor_dashboard">MainActivity</string>
    <string name="title_home">Home</string>
    <string name="title_dashboard">Dashboard</string>
    <string name="title_notifications">Notifications</string>


    <string name="new_1">Chronic Fever:
        When a person suffers from fever until 21 days and temperature does not become normal, it is called chronic fever. Sometimes, the temperature in this fever become high and sometimes low. If a person suffers from indigestion and weakness, he becomes the victim of chronic fever.
Treatment :

Prepare a decoction by boiling the bark of oval leaved rose way and tinospora and give to the patient to take. Or soak the bark of oval leaved rose way in the water at night and give this preparation after filtering to the patient. Both are beneficial in chronic fever.
Boil cow’s milk by mixing ghee, dry ginger and black grapes. Take it. Its use gets rid of chronic fever.
Grind equal quantity of chireta, dry ginger, Indian gooseberry (amla), sweet flag and tinospora. Fill it in a bottle. Then give 1-1 spoon of this preparation 3-4 times a day.
In the fever from which a patient has been suffering for 6 days and he gets no relief by any medicine, grind 40g tinospora properly and soak in 250 ml water filled in an earthen pot. Cover this pot and leave all over night. Crush this mixture in the morning and take 20 ml this preparation after filtering thrice a day. Its use provides relief in chronic fever.
Take 20 ml juice of tinospora after mixing 1g piper longum and one spoon honey in it in the morning and evening. Its use gets rid of chronic fever, cough, spleen diseases, phlegm, anorexia, etc.
To prevent headache due to fever, caused by dirty place, polluted environment and spoiled fruits-vegetables; boil 400 ml water with 10 to 20g leaves of white kachanar until it remains one-fourth. Now this decoction should be given to the patient.
It is very useful to take the decoction of neem’s bark after mixing coriander and dry ginger in it.
Grind 400 g leaves of neem, 120g dry ginger, black pepper, long peeper, triphala (Harad, Baheda and Aamla), all three types of salt, 80g impure carbonate of soda and impure carbonate of potash and 200g bishop’s weed to make powder. Now take this powder in the morning and evening. Its use provides relief in chronic fever.
Poisonous and chronic fever abates by taking the smoke of neem’s leaves, sweet flag, ghee, myrolealans, Indian bdellium and albizzia lebbeck (Shiras).
Prepare decoction by boiling equal quantity of neem’s bark, dry grapes and tinospora in 100 ml water. Take 20 ml this decoction in the morning, noon and evening for a few days regularly.
Tie 21 leaves of neem and 21 pieces of black pepper in muslin cloth to make a small bundle then boil it in 500 ml water until it remains one-fourth. Now give this water after cooling in the morning and evening to the patient in the condition of chronic fever. Its use provides relief to the patient of chronic fever.
Mix the juice of seedless unripe fresh fruits of bead tree with the same quantity of the juice of tinospora and one-fourth powder of bishop’s weed. Now make small tablets after grinding all properly. Then take 1-1 tablet thrice a day with fresh water. It gets rid of chronic fever.
Boil salt in water and take. Its use gets rid of malarial fever.
Grind 1 spoon powder of the bark of terminalia Arjuna with jiggery (gur). Its use gets rid of chronic fever.
If someone has been suffering from chronic fever along with cough and pain in the chest, it is useful to take the juice of basil’s leaves after mixing sugar candy in it.
 </string>
    <string name="new_2">
        i)THIGH PAIN:

Introduction :

A person suffers from pain in the muscles of thighs because of different reasons as by lifting heavy weight, cycling and running. In this case, the victim faces difficulty in sitting and standing.
Treatment :

Mix half spoon ghee with one spoon ginger juice and give it to the patient on empty stomach in the morning, it provides relief from thigh pain.






> ii)SWEAT IN HAND AND FEET:

Introduction :

Sweating is a common condition but if excessive sweat comes on the hand and feet in the summer or winter seasons while sitting, it is a type of disease. Sweat comes on the hand and feet without any reason during sitting in this disease.
Treatment :

Burn separate kandi and yellow coudi thereafter grind fine both together. Rub this mixture on the hand and feet, it reduces sweat.
Take about ¼ parts datura seeds to get relief in excessive sweat of the hand and feet.
Apply ground leaves of beriya on the hand and feet, it ends excessive sweat of the hand and feet.
Grind dry ginger and barrengtonia acutangula together and apply it on the hand and feet, it reduces sweat quantity
Mix powder of myrabalan chebulie with ground leaves of acacia Arabica and rub it on the hand and feet, it provides relief in excessive sweat. Rub dried leaves of acacia Arabica on the hand and feet to get relief too.
If the patient has been suffering from excessive sweat in feet, keep feet in lukewarm water thereafter keep it in cold water. Rub together both feet in cold water and mop it. Use this process for one week regularly, it provides relief in excessive sweat of the hand and feet.
 </string>
    <string name="new_3">NAILS PROBLEMS

Treatment :

If your nails have moved on, wash them with lukewarm water properly. Now grind ghee, turmeric and almond 10 grams each together then heat it. Apply this mixture on them, it provides relief.



























> i)NAILS ITCHING:

Introduction :

Nails’ itching is a type of disease, which spoils the nails. Nails thickness, curvedness, flatness, etc. are symptom of the nails itching. Sometimes, this itching decays the nails because of which they appear rough.
Treatment :

Apply ground root of yellow datura on the nails 2-3 times in a day regularly, it ends nails itching.
Make ointment by mixing one gram camphor and one gram sulphur with kerosene. Apply this ointment on the nails 2-3 times in a day regularly, it provides relief in nails itching.
Grind big myrabalan chebulie with vinegar and apply it on the nails 2-3 times in a day regularly, it ends nails itching.
Grind upper bark of coconut and apply it on the nails 2-3 times in a day regularly, it provides relief in nails itching.
Rub coconut oil on the nails, it increases shiny and age of the nails.
Papaya juice should be applied on the nails after scratching to end nails itching.
Apply Harsingar juice on the nails after scratching, it is useful to end itching or decomposition of the nails.
Apply juice of sprouted of pudding pipe on the nails, it is useful to end nails itching.
Apply Chidchida ground leaves on the nails 2-3 times in a day regularly, it ends nails itching.
Apply Guma juice on the nails 2-3 times in a day regularly, it ends decomposition of the nails and provides relief from pain.
Grind well equal quantity of borax, toasted alum, amlasar, sulphur and sugar together then mix white Vaseline in it. Apply this mixture on the nails 2-3 times in a day regularly, it provides relief in itching and decomposition of the nails.
Kamala:
Make a decoction by boiling 20-40 grams runia cardfolia with water and take it 2-3 times in a day regularly, it ends nails itching.
Make a powder by grinding green coach grass and turmeric together. Mix this powder with jaggery of sugarcane and heat it. Apply it on the nails to get relief in pain and decomposition of the nails.
Put nails in light hot oil of castor for few times and rub this mixture on the nails also, it increases shine of the nails within some times. If sinking nails in lukewarm oil is not possible, soak cotton in this oil and apply it on the nails.
Grind turmeric and coach green grass with neem leaves then heat it on fire. Apply it on the nails and tie bandage, it ends nails itching.
Mix sesamem alkali with impure carbonate of potash and apply it on the affected nails, it brings out pus from the nails. There is no need to dissection during this process.
Tie ground leaves of pomegranate on the broken nails to get relief from pain.
Grind some quantities of khorasan thorn, myrabalan chebulie with pomegranate flowers. Filling this mixture in the nails to get relief in swelling and pain of the nails.
Squeeze lemon in lukewarm water and put the fingers in this water for 5 minutes after just put this hand in cold water. Use this process, it increases nails.
Nails become beautiful and strong by applying lemon juice on the front of nails then dry it.


















> ii)NAILS WOUND:

Introduction :

The wound, which occurs in the corner of the nails of the finger due to inflammation, is called nails wound. The patient feels unbearable pain in this disease.
Treatment :

Mix the fine powder of turmeric with jaggery and heat it on fire. Tie this mixture on the affected part, it provides relief in nails wound.
Grind myrabalan chebulie with water and mix honey in it. Apply this mixture on the nails; it cures wound and pain of the nails soon.
Mix coriander powder with barley-flour and apply it on the nails as well as tie bandage upon it. It provides relief in wound and inflammation of the nails.
Mix dikamali with water and store it. Soak bandage in this mixture properly and tie it on the nails, it cures nails wound.
Mix kamala with oil and apply it on the nails, it all types of wound of the nails.
Take the decoction of black helle-bore twice a day regularly to get relief from pain caused by nails wound.
Apply ground seeds of staff tree on the nails; it is useful to end inflammation and wound of the nails soon.
Wound and inflammation of the nails are cured by dripping oil of bay-berry on the nails.
Mix 20 ml sesame oil, 10 grams vinegar and 5 grams ground mustard together. Heat this mixture and prepare ointment from it. Apply this ointment on the affected part, it cures nails wound caused by tear.
Nails wound is cured by tying ground leaves of pomegranate on the affected.
Tie bandage on broken nail and urinate on it, it provides relief from pain and cures wound of the nails.
Grind salt and mango powder together then mix it with water. Wound and pain are cured by applying this mixture on the affected.
If someone has been suffering from nails wound caused by root out nails, wash the nails with lukewarm water. Now grind turmeric, ghee and almond 10 grams each together properly. Apply this mixture on the nails, it provides relief in pain and wound.
 </string>
    <string name="new_4">INFLAMMATION OF HANDS AND FEET:

Introduction :

Itching of the hand and feet is called Inflammation of hands and feet. Swelling does not occur with it, but patient feels excessive inflammation and is being forced to sink his hands and feet in water. Mostly, this type of disease is found in women.
Treatment :

Take 6-10 grams gulakanda with milk or water twice a day, it is useful to end inflammation of the hand-feet, soles and eyes and blowing water from the eyes.
Rub ground leaves of fenugreek on the affected part; it ends inflammation of hands and feet.
Mix equal quantity of onion juice and mustard oil together. Rub this mixture on the affected part to get relief in inflammation of hands and feet.
Mix castor oil with goat milk and rub it on the hand and feet, it provides relief in inflammation of hands and feet.
Grind well leaves of five leaved chast and apply it on the hand and feet, it provides relief in inflammation of hands and feet.
Oil of mustard or sandal can be rubbed on the affected part because it ends inflammation of hands and feet.
Rub pumping seeds on the hand and feet and wash it with brackish water after few times. Use this process regularly; it is useful to end inflammation of hands and feet
Apply Shadpushpi ground seeds on the hand and feet, it ends inflammation of hands and feet. This medicine provides cold to the hand and feet.
Apply ground leaves of plum on the hand and feet, it provides relief in inflammation of hands and feet and excessive sweat.
Apply ground garden perslane on the hand and feet, it reduces inflammation of the hand and feet.
Inflammation of hands and feet is ended by rubbing cow ghee on the affected part.
Inflammation of hands and feet is ended by applying ground leaves of heena.
Lick one gram bamboo manna with honey twice a day to get relief in inflammation of hands and feet and excessive sweat.
Grind dried leaves (Dry leaves in shadow) of acacia arabica and rub it on the hand and feet, it provides relief. Acacia arabica leaves can be rubbed on the hand and feet to end excessive sweat too.
Milk alum with water and wash palm and soles with this water, it ends excessive sweat and inflammation of hands and feet.
Rub oil of sandal or mustard on the feet soles, it provides relief in inflammation of hands and feet.
Mix equal quantity pf butter and sugar candy together. Take 2 spoons this mixture in the morning regularly; it provides relief in inflammation of hands and feet.
Inflammation of hands and feet is ended by rubbing mango blossom (the flower, which appears before fruit) on the hand and feet.
Make a paste by grinding fresh wild onion on stone piece and apply it on the feet soles twice a day, it provides relief in inflammation of hands and feet.





















> i)INFLAMMATION IN FEET SOLES:

Introduction :

Inflammation in the soles of feet occurs because of different kinds of causes because of which the patient has to face great difficulty in walking.
Treatment :

Inflammation in the soles of feet occurs because of different kinds of causes because of which the patient has to face great difficulty in walking.
Luffa(Louki) marrow should be applied on the feet soles to end warmth and inflammation of the feet.
Inflammation of feet soles is ended by rubbing cut luffa on the soles.
Apply mustard oil on the hand and feet or feet soles, it provides relief in inflammation.
Mix one spoon mustard oil with 2 glass water and put the feet in this water for 5 minutes regularly. Scratch the feet with any rough thing and wash with cold water, it cleans the feet and ends warmth of the feet.
If someone has been suffering from feet inflammation caused by summer season, apply heena on his feet, it cures inflammation.
Rub mango blossom (the flower, which appears before fruit) on the hand and feet, it is useful to end inflammation.
Grind equal quantity of dried coriander and sugar candy together. Take 2 spoons this mixture with cold water 4 times in a day; it is useful to end inflammation of the hand and feet.
Mix equal quantity of butter and sugar candy together then apply it on the hand and feet, it ends inflammation.
Soak 2 spoons tragacanth gum in one glass water at overnight. In the next morning, Mix loaf sugar in this mixture and give it to the patient, it ends inflammation of the hand and feet. This medicine can be taken in the any season but it is very useful for in the summer season.
Rub juice of bitter guard leaves on the feet sole, it cures soles inflammation. Bitter juice can be used too.


> ii)FEET RINGWORM:

Introduction :

When any type of ringworm occurs on the feet and increases it with itching, it is called feet ringworm. The skin becomes black day-by-day due to swelling in this disease. Small pimples occur around of the ringworm and sticky pus comes out from it (pimples). This ringworm occurs due to a fungus infection of tinea trichophyton named germ.
Treatment :

Take about 3-50 ml juice of East Indian globe thistle 4 times in a day regularly, it purifies the blood and cures all diseases of the skin.
20-90 ml trifala juice should be taken 4 times in a day regularly because it purifies the blood and cures all diseases of the skin.
All types of blood disorders are ended by taking 50-100 ml juice of common fumitory 4 times in a day.
Mix ground rubia cardfolia with honey and apply it on the affected part. It is useful to cure all types of ringworm and blood diseases.
Grind bark of mudar root with water and apply it on the affected part, it provides relief in ringworm.














> iii)Decomposition of feet finger:

Introduction :

Toes of those persons who work in water for long time start to decay.
Treatment :

If someone has been suffering from decomposition of feet fingers, apply mustard oil on his affected part and spray henna. Mix 50 grams turmeric and 100 grams henna and take it twice a day; it provides relief in decomposition of the feet fingers caused by more in water.
If someone has been suffering from decomposition of the feet fingers due excessively working in water, mix one spoon heena with half spoon turmeric with one spoon of henna and apply it on his fingers twice a day regularly. It provides relief. It can be used in roughness or wound of the hand too. If any part of body becomes decayed, henna should be used to get excessive relief.
If decomposition or wound occurs on the feet fingers due to working in water, wash the fingers with catechu water and apply dried powder of catechu too. It provides relief.
 </string>
    <string name="new_5">Accidental Poisoning by Soap Products:
        Overview

Accidental poisoning by soap products can occur as a result of contact with household cleaning products that contain strong chemicals, such as simple soap and benzalkonium chloride. When these products are swallowed or inhaled they can be highly toxic, and even life-threatening.

What Causes Accidental Soap Poisoning?

People can be poisoned by soap or household cleaning products when they are exposed to them for a prolonged period. Often, people do not realize the strength of the products they are using. They may not open the windows for ventilation because they do not realize they are inhaling chemical fumes while cleaning.

Children may accidentally poison themselves if they are left unsupervised and ingest or inhale the soap products.

Risk Factors: Adults vs. Children

Adults may experience accidental poisoning while cleaning at home or work. Poisoning can occur if you do not follow the instructions for proper product use during cleaning.

However, children tend to be at a higher risk for accidental poisoning from soap or cleaning products because they are more likely to drink or eat these products without realizing that they are toxic.

Recognizing the Symptoms of Accidental Soap Poisoning

The symptoms of soap poisoning will depend on how the affected person was poisoned and how much contact they had with the soap products. If the soap or detergent has come into contact with your skin, you may have irritation, small holes, or even burns on top layer of skin. If you have inhaled fumes from soap products, you may have difficulty breathing or have swelling in your throat. This is very serious because difficulty breathing or swallowing can be life-threatening.

If soap has come into contact with your eyes or throat, other complications can arise. If soap gets in your eyes, you may have loss of vision or difficulty focusing because the chemicals may be burning your eyes. If you swallowed the soap, there may be pain or swelling in your throat and on your lips and tongue.

If you have been poisoned, you may have low blood pressure or your heart rate may drop rapidly. In serious situations, your heart could collapse from contact with the chemicals. Blood tests may reveal that the acid (pH) level of your blood has changed, which can damage your vital organs. This does not always occur with household soap products, but may happen with poisoning from commercial cleaning products.

Effects on your gastrointestinal tract should also be monitored. If you have been poisoned, you may begin to vomit repeatedly and you may vomit blood. You may also experience abdominal pain or have blood in your stool. Depending on the product that you ingested, you may also have burns in your esophagus.

Treatment for Poisoning in an Emergency Situation

Treatment for soap poisoning will vary depending on how you have been exposed to the chemical products. In most cases, a doctor will begin by checking your vital signs, including your pulse, temperature, blood pressure, and breathing. If you know how much or what kind of exposure you have had to soap products, you should tell the medical team right away. Treatment for soap poisoning may include:
oxygen
pain medication
a breathing tube
IV fluids
removal of any burned skin
skin irrigation (washing the skin repeatedly)
a bronchoscopy (a camera put down your throat to check for burns in the lungs and airways)
an endoscopy (a camera put down your throat to check for burns in the esophagus and stomach)
Poisoning can be life-threatening; you must seek treatment immediately to help prevent severe complications, including brain damage and tissue death.
 </string>
    <string name="new_6"> MRSA

MRSA (methicillin resistant staphylococcus aureus) is a type of staphylococcus bacteria (staph) that is resistant to beta-lactam antibiotics. MRSA is contagious and can cause life-threatening infection. MRSA isn’t found in the natural environment (soil or water). It lives in the nose and on the skin of humans. MRSA is spread by coming in contact with an infected person or by exposure to a MRSA-contaminated object or surface that an infected person touches.  Risk Factors for Developing a MRSA Infection  Risks for HA-MRSA  Risks for HA-MRSA include:  hospitalization (current or within the past year) dialysis weakened immune system nursing home residence Risks for CA-MRSA  Risks for CA-MRSA include:  prison residence homosexual sex (homosexuals have a higher incidence of MRSA) athletes who share equipment, towels, or razors participation in contact sports residence in military training camps attendance at day care facilities touching surfaces contaminated with MRSA Symptoms and Signs of a MRSA In
 </string>
    <string name="new_7"> Bullae
What Are Bullae?  Bullae are fluid-filled sacs or lesions that appear when fluid is trapped under a thin layer of your skin. Bullae are similar to blisters and vesicles, with the only difference being in size.  Vesicles are about the size of the top of a pin, reaching a maximum size of about 10 millimeters in diameter. After this point, a vesicle is considered a blister. When a blister becomes larger than 1 centimeter in diameter, it is a bulla. (Bulla is the singular form of bullae.)  What Causes Bullae?  Bullae and blisters are common occurrences that can be caused by various medical and environmental factors.  Friction  One of the most common causes of bullae is friction, such as the friction that occurs from using a shovel or other tool, or rubbing against a shoe. Friction blisters appear most often on your hands and feet.  Contact Dermatitis  If you come into contact with things that irritate your skin, like latex, cosmetics, or poison ivy, you could develop a condition called contact dermatitis
 </string>
    <string name="new_8">Chest Pain

> i)RIB PAIN:

Introduction :

The veins become tight due to check phlegm in the lungs because of that patient suffer from ribs pain. Sometimes, when the patient suffers from cold, phlegm stops on the upper side and does not come out. The parson who takes such types food stuff, which originate gas, suffers from this disease. This disease occurs due to taking cold food stuff and cold weather.
Symptoms :

The pain occurs in the body due to air affects. Unbearable pain occurs in the chest. The sweat comes out on the patient forehead because of that uneasiness of the patient increases.
Meal and abstinence :

The patient who suffers from rib pain should not take cold food stuff. Light hot oil should be rubbed on the affected part. It ends coldness and provides relief in disease.
Treatment :

Mix 20 grams caraway and 5 buds of garlic with 250 ml mustard oil. Boil this mixture on light fire until half oil remains then filter it and fill in bottle. Rub this oil on the chest and ribs, it provide relief in pain.
Mix half pinch shrung ash with garlic juice and take it with honey, it provides relief in ribs pain.
Rub camphor on the chest and ribs, it is useful to cure pain.
Suck cloves, it reduces cough and brings out phlegm easily. Clove is useful to cure cough, asthma and breathing problems.
Boil 5 basil leaves and cloves with milk. Give this preparation to the children, it makes the chest strong and stops ribs pain.
Grind asafoetida with water and coat it on the ribs, it provides relief from pain.
Grind 30 grams dry ginger and boil it with water. Take this preparation, it provides relief in all types of pain of the ribs.
Mix some vermillion with honey and coat it on clean cloth. Stick this cloth on the affected part and foment it, it provides relief in ribs pain soon.
Ribs pain disappears by taking lukewarm water after meals.
Boil one spoon caraway with 250 ml water until ¼ parts remains then filter. Take 2 spoons this hot decoction at bedtime regularly; it provides relief in ribs pain within 2-4 days.
Grind asafoetida and horn of barasinga with dhatura juice and makueya juice. Coat it on the ribs, it provides relief in pain.
Grind one gram pure blue copper shulphat with kanja seeds and mix it with pulp of idoran fruit. Prepare tablets (equal of ¼ parts) from it. Tie these tablets on the ribs part, it provides relief from pain.
Grind asafoetida with lukewarm water and rub it on the ribs, it provides relief in pain.
Grind some black sesame with mudar milk until turns into dark pest then heat it. Coat it on the affected ribs and coat sesame oil on mudar leaf there after heat this leaf on grid and tie it on the affected ribs with bandage. It is useful to cure ribs pain.
Boil 30 grams dry ginger with 500 ml water and filter it. Take this preparation 4 times in a day, it provides relief in pain.
Grind sambhar horn with water and mix it with honey. This preparation should be coated on the ribs to get relief in rib pain.
Mix 10 ml lemon juice, 3 grams impure carbonate of potash and 6 grams honey together. Take this mixture, it provides relief from pain of the ribs, heart and stomach.



















> ii)PNEUMONIA:

Introduction :

When the swelling occurs in the lungs due to any cause, it is called pneumonia. The one lung suffers from swelling in this disease but if both lungs suffer from swelling, it is called double pneumonia. Swelling of the lungs is called pneumonia. In this case, the lungs become hard due to swelling. If this disease occurs in the children, it is called rickets. It is a condition of sinnipatta fever.
Causes :

Pneumonia is caused by changing weathers, hard work, drinking excessive cold water, living in cold air and taking cold food stuff. Some doctors consider that pneumonia occurs due to specially germs. Treatment of this disease should be done soon otherwise it may be the cause of death.
Symptoms :

First of all, pneumonia patient feels cold and after that he suffers from fever. Eyes and face of the patient become red and he suffers from excessive thirst. Tongue becomes dirty, headache, anorexia; fits with dried cough, chest warmth, breathing problems, lungs become decay, etc. are symptoms of this disease. It is a hard disease and also increases. When the fever becomes fast in this disease, ribs pain originates with cough. In this case, the phlegm checks in the patient chest and he suffers from suffocate. The patient feels voice of phlegm while breathing in the chest. Holes occur in the down part of lungs and face becomes rough. The patient feels mystification and his lips become blue. The pain occurs in ribs and tongue becomes black after drying in this disease.
Meal and abstinence :

The patient should take easy digestible food stuff in pneumonia and rest. Sesapadula, ribbed luffa, bitter gourd, apple, and pomegranate, and spinach, juice of hoarse gram and bread of barley or wheat should be taken. Mix ginger with cow milk and take it at noon. Boiled water should be drunk after cooling (drought by drought). The patient must walk after meal. Sugar or honey should be used with milk.
Greasy food stuff as ghee and oil should not be taken. Exercise, physically or mentally hard work, sex, cold water, anger, sleeping in day, milk and milky food stuff should not be used. Sour, pithi, sweets of fine-flour, water-melon, meat, fish and betel should not be taken.

Treatment :

Grind barahsinga with water and coat it on the ribs. It is useful to cure pneumonia.
Make a powder by grinding equal quantity of radish seeds and pistachia intergerma together. Giving ¼ parts this powder to the children with ghee and honey for 6 hours (to lick) is useful to cure asthma breathing problems and pneumonia of the children.
Take 1-3 grams powder of runia cardfolia with honey thrice a day regularly; it cures pneumonia, swelling and pain.
Fomenting front and back part of the chest with salt poultice brings out phlegm after melting and provides relief in pain swelling and pneumonia.
If any child has been suffering from whirr of the throat and chest, mix 10-20 drops juice of leaves of red Malabar-nut with toasted borax or small peppers and take it with honey after every 4-6 hours. It brings out phlegm from the chest and cures swelling caused by pneumonia.
Mix juice of 4 leaves of black Malabar-nut, juice of horse radish bark, salt and honey together. Swelling and inflammation of the lungs are cured by taking it regularly.
Mix salt with cow urine and take it in half spoon quantity twice a day. It is useful to cure pneumonia.
Take 10-20 ml juice of five leaved chest leaves twice a day as well as grind Indian five leaved and leaves of Indian beach, neem and datura together. Heat this mixture and apply it on the chest. Cloth should be tied on the chest after coating it. Use this process for some days regularly; it is useful to cure swelling and pain of the lungs.
Pneumonia is cured by taking a decoction of leaves of five leaved chast regularly.
Grind 3 grams toasted borax with 3 grams toasted blue copper sulphate and mix ginger juice in it. Prepare tablets (equal of millet) from this mixture and dry it in shadow. Give one tablet to the children with breast milk twice a day; it is useful to cure pneumonia.
Mix one pinch puffed borax, one pinch puffed alum, one spoon basil juice, one spoon ginger juice and half spoon juice of betel leaf together. Mix this mixture with honey and take it twice a day. It provides very relief in pneumonia.
Mix 5 ml garlic juice with 20 grams honey and give it to the patient to lick thrice a day regularly. It is useful to cure pneumonia.
Mix one spoon garlic juice with lukewarm water and give it to the patient to drink. It is useful to cure pneumonia.
Toast garlic pods in fire and prepare powder from it. Take one pinch this powder with honey 3-4 times in a day; it is useful to cure inflammation and swelling of the lungs.
Pneumonia is cured by taking one spoon garlic juice with lukewarm water.
Mix 2 grams camphor with 10 ml turpentine oil and rub it on the ribs. It provides relief in pneumonia.
Mix camphor with 4 folds mustard oil and rub it on the ribs to cure pain.
Make a decoction by boiling Indian cinnamon, big cardamom, cobra saffron, camphor, cubeb, eagle wood and cloves with water. Pneumonia is cured by taking this decoction twice a day.
Mix one spoon ginger juice with one spoon basil juice and take it with honey to cure pneumonia.
Mix old ghee (1-2 years old) and camphor with ginger juice there after heat it. Rub this mixture on the chest, it provides relief in pneumonia.
If someone has been suffering from pneumonia, fill ¼ parts asafoetida in 3-4 dry grapes and take it thrice a day. It is useful to cure pneumonia within one week.
Boil 20 grams green leaves of basil, 5 black peppers, 3 cloves, 2 pinches turmeric and one knot ginger with water until half water remains then filter it. Take this decoction twice a day for 10 days regularly; it is useful to cure pneumonia.
Mix equal quantity of dry ginger, juice of basil leaves and powder of long peppers together. Pneumonia is cured by taking it.
Grind 5 black peppers with 20 ml juice of green leaves of basil and give it to the patient to cure pneumonia.
Digestive activity of the patient becomes effect in the pneumonia, so pure honey should be rubbed on the chest and ribs as well as honey should be taken with lukewarm water.
Make a powder by grinding Indian gooseberry, cumin seed, long peppers, and seeds of cow hage and myrabalan chebulie together. Pneumonia is cured by taking this powder with honey twice a day.
Apply ground fruit of cuttle fish bone on the children chest, it is useful to cure pneumonia.
Take 3-6 grams powder of Naagdanti root with cinnamon twice a day, it is useful to cure pneumonia soon.
If any small child suffers from mystification in the chest and cough, give 1-2 drops Bahngreya juice to the child thrice a day regularly, it cures rickets.
Pneumonia is cured by taking 3-6 grams powder of Ranicool panchang (axis, root, leaves, fruit and flower) with honey.
Put bark of Large flowered agati root in betel nut and suck it or taking 10-20 ml juice of large flowered agati twice a day brings out phlegm. Use it brings out sweat and reduces fever slowly.
Mix fresh juice of mint with honey and take it after every one hour. It is useful to cure pneumonia.
Toast 2 long peppers on fire and grind it. Mix this powder with one spoon honey and give it to the children thrice a day. It is useful to cure rickets.
Heat juice of neem leaves there after rub it on the chest to cure pneumonia.
 </string>
    <string name="new_9"> MENTAL

> i) ANGER

Introduction :

When a person has to work against his will or there is tension because of any reason, he shows his tension through his voice or his attitude. It is called anger. Voice of the angry person becomes heavy and he speaks with irritation. Mostly, anger occurs because of bile disorders, disorders in ligaments and mentally tension. If there is anger in normal condition or conversation, it is due to bile disorder.
Treatment :

Take 1-2 gram powder of rauwolfia serpentina everday before going to bed. Its use ends the anger and irritation gently. This formula cools down the anger that produces because of high blood pressure or other reasons.
Take sugar candy and black pepper corns with 10 ml juice of corchorus olitorius. Its use ends anger and irritation produced due to bile. Besides it, the patient evacuates clearly and his constipation breaks by its use.
Take about 3-6 grams powder of winter cherry (nagauri) mixing with sugar candy and ghee with lukewarm milk twice a day. Its use ends ligament disorder and the patient becomes free from anger.
Anger cools down by eating the powder of sweet flag root mixing with honey twice a day regularly.
Mix 7-10 ml juice of tinospora with honey and take twice a day. Its use soothes anger produced due to bile disorder.
Anger comes down by taking 25-50 ml decoction of fiumaria indica twice a day. Its use ends the heat produced due to bile. Anger cools down by its use.
Inflammation and giddiness as well as anger disappear by eating 1-2 jam of Indian gooseberry.
Prepare a decoction by boiling panchang of mimosu pudica. Take bath with this water, it ends irritation and soothes anger.
Mix honey with about half gram muktapisti and lick. Its use cools down anger and irritation.
A person should drink 15 ml lemon juice for normalizing fast heart pulsation because of anger.




> ii) DEPRESSION

Causes :

A person can become the victim of depression because of several causes in life. It can occur because of failure, contemplation about family, illness or many other causes. The main cause of depression is lack of confidence or total loss confidence. When there is a lack of confidence, a person becomes the victim of depression. Depression can occur in human life due to lack of anything.
If a person surrounded by anxiety or troubles, he should not hide these problems in heart. He should share his problems with others viz relatives or friends because they console him and in this way he gets a solution of his problems. Try to pass the time with your friends so that you may not feel loneliness and remain far from depression. You should go library, museum and in cultural programs where you will feel light by doing this. In this way, you will get a power viz confidence fighting against problems and difficulties. If there is lack of sleeping at night, you should read light short stories or listen to stories.

If you want to reach anywhere on right time, you should left home early. There is no need to be worry if you are delay because of any cause. If there is a pressure or load of work, you need not to be nervous but do the work patiently. Do not work constantly while finishing the work but eat something or do something you like according to taste or interest. You can also walk. When you feel exhaustion while working, gossip with your friend. You should not be obstinate if you want to get free from depression. Contemplation is better than worry. A person should pray to GOD. Depression reduces by doing this.

Treatment :

Grind cinnamon with water and apply on the forehead. Its use stops headache and ends depression.
Jasmine is good medicine for the treatment of depression.
If a weak person has been suffering from depression, he should smell henna flowers and apply its flowers paste on the forehead.
Grind soap nut fruit with 1-2 black peppers and pour 4-5 drops of this preparation into the nose. Its use ends migraine.
Mix one spoon purgative oil with three spoons olive oil. Massage head with this oil after cutting hair. Its use vanish depression.
If there is excessive inflammation or heat, extract juice by grinding coach grass and apply all over the body. The person gets a lot of relief by its use.
Mental weakness ends and memory enhances by taking sweet beet juice or its salad.
Drink 250 ml juice of carrot regularly ends depression. Persons, who work in offices or students who are preparing for examination should take carrot juice necessarily. Its use proves very beneficial.
Mix one spoon oil of nigella in one cup of hot water. Drink this preparation at night before going to bed. Its use ends depression.
Prepare a paste by grinding flowers of Persian lilac. Its use ends the itching of the brain.
Grind castor root with edipta Alba juice and smell. Its use creates sneezing and headache ends.





























> iii) FORGETFULNESS

Introduction :

Sometimes, the brain of a person gets affected along with the body because of any accident or injury. Any injury is harmful for the brain and the memory of a person becomes weak. In this case, the victim starts to forget small things.
Causes :

Weakness of the body, excessive decay of semen, too much activeness and sexual urge and sexual relations become the causes of weak memory.
Treatment :

Grind 3 grams nigella seeds with honey and take in the morning. Its use provides relief in this disease.
Grind dry ginger, pulp of ivy gourd, nut grass each 25 grams and take it in the morning with water. Its use ends this disease named forgetfulness.
Grind 50 grams bacopa (brahm booti) with 5 grams ground powder of black pepper. Sieve it and take it with milk or water in the morning. Its use ends this disease named forgetfulness.
Grind thickly 25 grams root of Arabian manna plant dried in shadow and boil in 250 ml water until it remains 14. Sieve it and mix with half spoon ghee. Take it after heating it a little. Its regular use twice a day for one week cures this disease.
 </string>
</resources>